<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Notes on Blogophonic</title><link>/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research Notes on Blogophonic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Addressing social isolation and loneliness and the power of human connection</title><link>/research/position-statement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/position-statement/</guid><description>According to Badcock et al. (2022, p.2), social connection spans a variety of relationships from strong ties to family and friends to weaker ties to acquaintances and strangers. We speak of those relationships that you can rely upon for support and trust, where such relationships are of high quality and satisfying. Positive &amp;ldquo;social connections [are] vital to our health and wellbeing, while lacking or poor quality social connections [lead to the opposite result]&amp;rdquo; (p.</description></item><item><title>Define yourself by your next shot, not your last shot.</title><link>/research/define-yourself-by-your-next-shot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/define-yourself-by-your-next-shot/</guid><description>In this article, Colter Reed (n.d.) writes about a topic known to psychologist as, emotional refractory period, which he explains is &amp;ldquo;the amount of time it takes you to process the emotion of an event.&amp;rdquo; In his article, Reed highlights how Tiger Woods &amp;ndash; the winner of no less than 82 all-time PGA TOUR victories (&amp;ldquo;82 PGA Tour Career Victories,&amp;rdquo; n.d.) &amp;ndash; is a master of the emotional refractory period.</description></item><item><title>How to Combat Emotional Triggers.</title><link>/research/how-to-combat-emotional-triggers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/how-to-combat-emotional-triggers/</guid><description>Johnson (2022, March 25) explains that when someone says they are &amp;ldquo;triggered,&amp;rdquo; what this person means is that some event (a conversation, an observation, an altercation) directly influenced within them an unexpected emotional behavior that can result in negative consequences in mood, anxiety, or emotional state. An unexpected event occurs (the trigger), and the patient responds in response.
Not to put a personal note on this, but I have several emotional triggers, never mind their source.</description></item><item><title>Our Epidemic of Loneliness and Isolation</title><link>/research/epidemic-of-social-isolation-and-loneliness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/epidemic-of-social-isolation-and-loneliness/</guid><description>In 2023, our nation&amp;rsquo;s Surgeon General addressed a silent struggle affecting millions with his release of a profound national advisory titled &amp;ldquo;Our Epidemic of Loneliness and Isolation.&amp;rdquo; This advisory highlights an expansive yet often overlooked health crisis, spotlighting the profound effects of social disconnection in our modern world (U.S. Department of Health &amp;amp; Human Services, 2023).
In his advisory, the Surgeon General promotes social connectedness or lack thereof as to what lies at the heart of our troubles.</description></item><item><title>Social Capital</title><link>/research/social-capital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/social-capital/</guid><description>Broadly speaking, social capital is the accumulation of the efforts that we put into our relationships with others.
When we spend time and share conversations with our friends and family, we are creating what psychologists call, social capital.
This is a paragraph with a custom class applied to it.{.my-custom-class}
When we spend time and share conversations with our friends and family, we are building social capital from our relationships.{.bg-red}
{.ba .</description></item></channel></rss>