<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Blogophonic</title><link>/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Blogophonic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daily Check-In</title><link>/notes/daily-check-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/daily-check-in/</guid><description>With just a simple daily check-in, the UCKN Social Network helps keep members connected in groups defined by its members. It’s about ensuring that, despite the rush of life, there’s always a moment to connect with those who matter. Here, it&amp;rsquo;s the little updates, the daily &amp;lsquo;here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m up to&amp;rsquo; that keeps everyone in your chosen groups in the loop and connected.
It’s not about replacing phone calls or dinners out &amp;ndash; it’s about adding a thin layer of connection to your day, no matter how small, to remind us that we’re part of a community.</description></item><item><title>Social Capital</title><link>/notes/social-capital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/social-capital/</guid><description>Broadly speaking, social capital is the accumulation of the efforts that we put into our relationships with others.
When we spend time and share conversations with our friends and family, we are creating what psychologists call, social capital.
This is a paragraph with a custom class applied to it.{.my-custom-class}
When we spend time and share conversations with our friends and family, we are building social capital from our relationships.{.bg-red}
{.ba .</description></item><item><title>Tachyons for Style</title><link>/notes/tachyons-for-style/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/tachyons-for-style/</guid><description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort. Because Speed Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description></item><item><title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title><link>/notes/css-grid-scaffold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/css-grid-scaffold/</guid><description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.” — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips. Most times, while fighting with floats and widths of content and sidebars or just basically trying to get something beside something else without using a stupid TABLE.</description></item><item><title>Built-in Contact Form</title><link>/notes/built-in-contact-form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/built-in-contact-form/</guid><description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website. Functional Form This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used. Please use your actual email address.</description></item><item><title>My First Test Page</title><link>/notes/simple-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/simple-test/</guid><description>This is a test paragraph with a custom class applied.{.test-class}
This is a caption for the example image.</description></item></channel></rss>